

P: +966582733605 E: aziz.alhaj25@gmail.com Linkedin: https://bit.ly/3Eiad3w Google Scholar: https://bit.ly/3JJtdZT GitHub: https://bit.ly/3vyN6xB

TECHNICAL SKILLS

C/C++, Python, Matlab, JavaScript,
Dart, HTML, CSS, SQL
AutoCAD, Catia, Solidworks (CAD)
Computer Numerical Control
Machine (CNC)
Machine learning (ML)
Mobile Development | Flutter
PLC
Circuit Design | NI Multisim & Proteus
Microsoft Office
PowerRi

SOFT SKILLS

Problem solving
Teamwork
Leadership
Communication

LANGUAGES

Arabic • • • • • English

AFFILIATION & MEMBERSHIPS

The Institution Of Engineers, Malaysia | Student Member

REFERENCE

Anwar P.P. Abdul Majeed, PhD CEng MIMechE MIET SMIEEE Associate Professor-School of Robotics - Xi'an Jiaotong-Liverpool University

Address: 111 Ren'ai Rd., Dushu Lake Science & Education Innovation Town- Suzhou Industrial Park, P.R.

China.

Phone: +60164378902

ABDULAZIZ SALMAN

MECHATRONICS ENGINEER

ABOUT

A research assistant of sound localization systems via Al contemporary methods. I have a strong urge to prepare, analyze data, and construct models to assist organizations achieving their objectives, which resulted acquiring experiences of building various machine learning projects. I am a fast learner, and a problem solver, with high adaptability and ability to manoeuvre difficult tasks under high pressure. I am looking forward to having an honor to be a part of your community.

WORK EXPERIENCE

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Universiti Putra Malaysia| Oct 2021 - Current | Full-time

- Research assistant in sound localization and Al
- Co-supervised final year students for their final year projects
- A Lab assistant for two lab sessions, navigation and electric labs
- Supervised and assisted students for their study case project

AI ENGINEER

Aruvii Pte Ltd | July 2022 - Current

- Pose Estimation and action recognition
- Products dimension measurements and sent them through MQTT server through ROS
- Checking and counting rods diameter

MAINTENANCE INTERN ENGINEER

Top Glove Company | Aug 2020 - Oct 2020

- Investigated and found the root causes of hole on glove pouch
- Investigated the root causes of wrinkled wrappers and designed two mechanical systems as proposed solutions
- Digitized the usage of papers by built an android app with Google sheet monitor
- Investigated on root causes of weak seal, wrinkled seal and seal allowance of glove pouch
- Investigated and examined of the effectiveness of ionizers on electrostatic cloud

PUBLICATIONS

The Diagnosis Of Diabetic Retinopathy By Means Of Transfer Learning And Fine-Tuned Dense Layer Pipeline | https://bit.ly/3roJ21m | 2020

The Diagnostics of Osteoarthritis: A Fine-Tuned Transfer Learning Approach | https://bit.ly/3BXM9SZ | 2022

PROJECTS

Final Year Project

• The diagnosis of diabetic retinopathy by means of transfer learning and fine-tuned dense layer pipeline.

Rita conference

- Osteoarthritis Diagnosis: A Feature-based Transfer Learning Approach
 FaceNet
- Siamnse Nurel Network (SNN) and structural similarity index measure (SSIM)

Integrated Design Project (IDP)

 Built an Autonomous Following Trolley AFT by Means Global Positioning System

Programming for Engineers

• Built an IOT system to monitor the moisture of soil

COURSES

Institution of Engineers Malaysia | 10 Hours Matlab | November 2018 Introduction to Applied Machine Learning | coursera Nov 2020 Image Processing with Python | coursera Oct 2020 Face Recognition and You | Skymind 2022 MongoDB Basics | MongoDB University 2022 Deploying a Model for Inference at Production Scale | Nvidia 2022 Reinforcement Learning | University of Alberta 2022 PowerBi | Davidson College 2022

AWARDS

University Malaysia Pahang 6 Dean's List | Sep 2017 - June 2020

EDUCATION

B.ENG (HONS.) Mechatronics Engineering | Universiti Malaysia Pahang | 2017 - 2021 | CGPA 3.76 out of 4 | First Class Honor

MSc.Aerospace Engineering | Universiti Putra Malaysia | Oct 2021 - Current | Current CGPA 3.75 | Research Area : Audio-Based Relative Positioning for Rotorcraft UAVs Flying in Swarms Using Deep Learning.